Here we go again. Last week, we had
another Frontier model drop. Two of
them, actually. Claude Opus 4.5 and
Google's Gemini 3. And at this point,
keeping up with every new release feels
like a full-time job. So, in this video,
I want to share how I actually think
about evaluating new models when they
drop. And we'll put these two
heavyweights, Opus 4.5 and Gemini 3,
through a realworld test by building the
same app with both of them. Now, let me
be clear. There's really no way to
deliver a final verdict on any model
from a single test because a single
demo, whether it's by me or by you or
someone else, doesn't represent the full
range of projects and tasks that we
throw at these models day-to-day.
Planning a new feature looks different
from debugging an issue on production.
And green field development is different
from refactoring legacy code. You know,
I tend to find that some models are
better suited for different phases of
the product development cycle than
others. But even that is a very personal
preference. My workflow and style might
be different from yours. So, one model
might fit me like a glove, but you not
so much. So, when a new model drops and
I want to get a feel for it, I think the
move is to try it out on the types of
projects and tasks that are most
important to you. Now, for me, I care
most about planning and designing new
products and rapidly building them so
that I can deploy to first customers or
start using it myself. I care about
long-term maintenance, too, but I won't
really know how models perform there
until I've used them for months. So,
when we're in week one with a new model
or two new models like we are today, I
like to put them through their paces on
a fresh green field project, something
simple but real. And that's exactly what
we're going to do today. We're going to
build an invoicing app and we're going
to build it twice. Once using Opus 4.5
and again using Gemini 3. Same spec,
same requirements, head-to-head. We'll
go from planning to design to building
it out. And if you're looking to upgrade
your process for how you build with AI,
then I want to send you my builder
briefing. It's a five-minute read that I
send every week to cut through the noise
and help you keep a pulse on what's
actually working for professional
builders. You can get yours by going to
buildermethods.com.
And if you want to go deeper and connect
with other builders, my builder methods
pro membership is currently still on
sale for Black Friday. That's where I
share projectbased training, live
workshops, and we have a community of
builders who are figuring this out
together. Now's a great time to join us
by going to buildermethods.com/pro.
All right, let's build this thing. Okay,
so what we're going to do is build the
same app twice. So I've fired up two
separate codebases. The first one here I
named invoicy opus and then the other
one is named invoiceicy gemini. So these
are both rub on rails with inertia and
react and we'll be using Tailwind CSS
and some shad CN components. Now, the
process for designing and building this
app is going to be sort of a a speedrun
version of what I usually do. I I
usually take a much more methodical
approach, but for the purpose of this
demo, I want to get through the entire
design process and the building process
for a simple client invoicing
application. Now, what I've done in both
of these is I've added a folder called
plan. And inside that, I have a product
overview file. And this is basically
just an overview of the simple invoicing
app that we're going to build. You know,
I've got this information up here, some
information about the like the shell of
the application. We're going to have a
dashboard view. We're going to have a a
view for managing clients, a view for
managing invoices, uh the ability to
have like a sharable invoice view that
we can send to a client, and then I just
gave it some information on the tech
stack that we're working with. So, I'm
going to reference this product overview
when I give it the prompts. And I also
prepared two prompts that we're going to
be using because we're going to break
this very simple design and build
project into two phases. The first
phase, I want to see how these models
can handle designing a a professional
front-end interface for for the views in
this app. And then the second prompt is
where we will, you know, wire up the
back end and make it a functional
product. The other thing that I'll be
looking to do throughout this process is
to see how Opus 4.5 compares to Gemini
when it comes to planning and asking
clarifying questions. So let's get
started with this Opus project and see
how it can handle the first phase which
is planning and designing this
application. So, I'm going to run claude
code. And first I'm going to say uh
reference product overview for an
overview of what we will be building.
And then I'm going to go into this
prompt. And I guess I could just like
reference this prompt file as well, but
I'll just copy and paste it. And so to
show you what I just pasted in for this
first prompt is let's start with the
front-end design. We won't be building
the full API backend functionality just
yet. Start by stubbing out these routes
and views for the dashboard, clients,
invoices, invoice editor, and sharable
invoice. And then I'm saying use your
front-end design skill to design a clean
professional front-end design. So on my
system in my home directory, I have
installed a cloud code skill called
front-end design. And a couple weeks
ago, the team at Anthropic shared this
uh skill in this blog post called
improving front-end design through
skills. And I've been using this on a
bunch of recent projects, and it works
really great. So, you can see my
previous video about claude code skills
and what they are and and how they work.
Uh but the team actually provided a
specific skill skill that they call
front-end design. And I have that
installed in my home directory in my
claw directory in skills. And you can
see front-end design and it's this
simple build.md file. Anyway, you can
read more about that from their blog
post. I just copied it as is and it
works really great. So, it just adds a
little bit of design muscle to cla code.
So, we're going to use that in cloud
code and I'm also going to reference the
same skill in Gemini 3 when we do that.
It it's easy to do. So, we'll get into
that as well. So, so I'm telling it to
use that front-end design skill. I gave
it a few more requirements about, you
know, I want it to be mobile responsive.
I wanted to support light and dark
modes. Some information about how we're
using Tailwind, Google Fonts, Lucide
icons. When finished, just give me like
the five uh route URLs so that I can
easily preview them in the browser and
we can see what they what they look
like. All right. And and also I'm asking
it to start by asking me clarifying
questions to inform your plan for this.
And you know what? I'm actually going to
toggle into plan mode. Specdriven
development can take many different
forms. And today we're going to take
probably like the simplest possible
approach to this. So I always like to
start in plan mode and really dial in
the plan. Specifically, I want to see
how Opus 4.5 is going to ask me
constructive clarifying questions to
make sure that we're set up for success
here. All right, so I'm going to send
that prompt and let's get going. Okay.
And by the way, in the latest versions
of Cloud Code, I really like how they've
added this question and answer
interface, which makes it really easy
for me to, you know, select answers to
these uh questions that the agent is
posing back to me. I love this pattern
of having the agent ask me back
questions. It's such a powerful
underrated, I think, aspect to the
planning phase when it comes to building
stuff with AI. All right, so what Google
font would you like to use? I'm just
going to use it's since this is a
simpler app with just a few pages, we'll
go with a top navbar for the sharable
invoice page. Yes, this should be a
standalone layout. Okay, I'll submit
those answers. So, just evaluating Opus
4.5's ability to plan and ask questions.
I'd say I was pretty happy with those
questions. They all seemed pretty
accurate and constructive. So, something
I like to see. All right, let's see how
it does with putting together an
implementation plan here. By the way,
Claude Code has started actually saving
its plans. Yeah, you can see here. Um,
it it gives it these weird names.
Mutable greeting fog. What's kind of
weird to me is that it it actually saves
those plans in in the home directory in
in Claude in the cloud directory. And
then you can see inside plans, you'll
find it here, you know, with these kind
of cryptic names. I kind of wish that it
would have just saved the plan into my
codebase into my project. I guess I
could like instruct it to do that, but
it just seems weird. I would rather have
the plan in the actual project where the
plan happens. But anyway, here is the
plan. Yeah, that looks pretty good. I
see some design decisions. It's going to
stub out some routes. It's going to
create these page components. You know,
in a normal typical project, I would
spend a lot more time reviewing this
line by line, but I think I think this
is looking good. And yeah, let's go
ahead and have it um let's go ahead and
have it design these these front ends
for our app. Okay, so Opus 4.5 and cloud
code has completed its work. I'd say
that took about 10 minutes or so and and
here is its final report. Implementation
complete and it gave me the list of URLs
exactly as I asked for. We're going to
take a look at those in just a second.
We've got a list of components that was
built. Um, so I'm going to go ahead and
start my server. [clears throat] Okay,
so here is the the dashboard view. This
was created by Opus 4.5. And so, uh,
yeah, it went with that like emerald
green color. I do like I I do kind of
like this navigation centered across the
top. That's interesting. Created a nice
little icon and text logo there. One
thing I don't love is the double up of
this button. So, I assume that this is
going to be like a global button shown
on all pages. And here, since we're on
the dashboard, I've got like a new
client and a new invoice. So, just
visually, I don't like seeing these two
things together on the same page like
that. Um, but that's that can be
tweaked. Got this nice got this nice
metrics layout. Don't know if I love the
the weird padding on those, but that's
that's okay. Just the the designer in me
is being a little nitpicky, but I guess
that's the the point of this whole
exercise, right? This is a nice touch. I
like this like great progress this
month. Uh something I did not ask for,
but that's an interesting interesting
one. This stuff does actually follow the
the instruction that I gave it in terms
of what I want to see on this page. So,
I did ask it to support light mode and
dark mode, and it actually didn't do
that this time. Interestingly, I did a
test run of this project off camera
earlier, and it and it did handle dark
mode that time, but this time during
recording, it it did not. So, you know,
that's just another example of how you
can run the same prompt twice, even with
the exact same model, and sometimes
it'll just, you know, perform a little
bit better than others.
I did ask it to make it mobile
responsive. So, let's see how it did
with that. And that's that's looking
pretty good. Everything Everything does
break down. Everything does break down
uh pretty good. Although, I'm seeing
some some side scrolling bleed when we
get to a really small screen size there.
Got a nice mobile mobile slideout menu
there. That's That's kind of cool. Okay.
Pretty impressive. All right. So, that's
the dashboard view. Let's take a look at
the other views. Do these link? Yes.
Okay. So, here is the uh client list.
Looking pretty good. I don't love this
this this handling of the padding. A
little bit too close to the edge there
for my taste. Um once again, like the
two green buttons here a little bit
competing for my attention. Okay. So, we
got some nice menus here, some nice
sample data. That's looking pretty good.
Okay, it actually uh gave me like a new
client modal popup. Now, normally I
would like really plan out all these
little details during the spec and the
planning phase, but again, we're doing
sort of like a a speedrun uh test here.
So, here's the invoices view. Again,
like this this left padding is a little
bit tight for my taste. Um we do have
the filter, which is nice. Something
that I did ask for. A little bit hard to
read these numbers, but that's okay.
Let's let's see how that works on
mobile. This is so this is good. So, you
know, this is actually a hard thing to
do is to make a list like this collapse
down to a mobile view. And it it seemed
to do a really good job on that. Okay.
So, here is the invoice editor view. We
can select a client. We can add some
invoice items. Looks good. And let's see
the preview. Okay. So, that one doesn't
link, but I believe that it did actually
create that. So, here is that URL. And
that's okay that it doesn't link because
really I only asked it to to do the
mock-ups for now. We're going to do the
the back end wiring up here in just a
second. So here is the uh sharable
invoice which you know does look nice
and professional, nice and clean. One
thing I'm noticing again just a small
detail is like there's this extra space
due to the looks like it's due to the
rounded corner. Um and this gradient
really should go all the way to the top.
Just being very nitpicky about this, of
course. Um, and let's see how we look on
mobile. Okay. Yeah, it breaks down
nicely. So, overall, I'm I'm pretty
impressed. And there are some some
little details that I would normally
like spend a little bit of time
polishing up with with Claude. But, but
yeah, I think that's a really good
really good test run. Okay. So now let's
jump over to our project with Gemini 3
and we'll run the same process of
starting with the design of the
front-end views for this new uh
invoicing app. When I use Gemini or any
other model that is not a cloud model,
I'll use cursors agent mode for that. So
that's what we're going to do when we're
in this Gemini project. I'll just make
this a little bit bigger and I'm going
to switch the agent to Gemini 3 Pro and
I'm going to start in plan mode just
like I did in Claude Code. Cursor also
has a very nice and capable plan mode
here. Now, just like in the Opus
project, I also have this plan folder
here in the Gemini project. It has the
same product overview that I had over
there and I have the same prompt one and
prompt two, which we'll get to in a
little bit. Now the only difference here
in the Gemini project is that I added
this front-end design skill.m MD. So
this is literally that Claude code skill
for the front-end design that I used in
in Claude code. I want to make the same
skill or that same design muscle
available to Gemini to try to put them
on, you know, equal playing field here.
So, so I'm going to start by saying
refer to product overview for an
overview of what we will be building.
And then I'm going to go to prompt one
and I'm going to copy that in. Again, I
I guess I could just, you know,
reference it as well, but I just want to
make it clear that that's the prompt.
We're going to start with the front-end
design. We're going to have it stub out
these routes and views. I gave it a few
requirements and and that's good. Now,
here is just one thing I want to tweak
for Gemini. Since it doesn't quite have
that claude code skills feature, I'm
going to rewrite this part. Um, refer to
front-end design skills. So, I'm
literally referring to this file right
here and use that skill set to design a
clean, professional front-end design,
UIUX for these views. So, hopefully that
will be good. Now again, we're still in
plan mode, and I'm just going to ask it
to ask me clarifying questions to inform
its plan. So, cursor in plan mode also
has a very nice question and answer
interface, just like Claude Code does. I
love how all these tools are really
starting to converge on the same set
sets of features and the same paradigms.
I think that's that's really great for
all of us. So, here's the first
question. So, it's asking me like which
design aesthetic should it lean toward?
That that's an interesting question. a
little bit different from what Opus was
asking me. Yeah, let's go with modern
SAS. What's your preferred navigation
layout? Similar question to what Opus
asked me. Uh, we'll go with the top bar
navigation since this is like a simpler
app with just a few links. How would you
like me to handle dummy data for these
views? That's a really interesting
question because it's part of a new
design process that I'm that I've been
tinkering with myself is uh generating
sample data first. Again, it's a little
bit, you know, again, that was just a
little bit too much process for this
simple demo. But Gemini 3 is is sort of
thinking along the same lines as how I'm
thinking about my my new design process.
So, yeah, let's go with a centralized
mock data. That's that's good. Shall I
add more SHA shad CN? Yes. And install
the standard ones. Okay. So, these were
these were very good questions. I would
say I was pretty impressed with uh
Gemini's thoughtful, constructive
planning questions here. Okay, so that
plan is all set and I can I can review
it here. One of the nice things I like
about plan mode in cursor is I can just
click this button to save it to the
workspace and it does that. It puts it
right into the actual workspace into the
project unlike cloud code which for some
reason puts it in my home directory. I
do wish it would just save it
automatically or if there was a setting
for that, but at least it's it's right
here. And I also like that the that it
has a more relevant name for the plan or
this this is essentially a spec, if you
will. So, yeah, here it is. Here's the
plan. Looks pretty good. And
interestingly, you know, I've seen I've
seen it do this before. I don't know if
this is a Gemini 3 thing or maybe an
issue with cursor, but it actually
didn't create to-dos. Uh, sometimes I
need to give it a little bit of a nudge.
Create your to-do list for this plan.
And I've only started seeing it do that
since I've started experimenting with
Gemini 3. So, that's that's an
interesting quirk. Okay, so now it added
its 10step to-do list to its plan. And
uh, yeah, that's all looking good. So, I
guess sometimes you just got to give it
a little nudge, right? So, I'm going to
go ahead and press the build button to
have it start designing the frontends.
And I do have Gemini 3 Pro selected as
the model for that. So let's go ahead.
[clears throat] Okay, so it's completed
its work now. And I would say it took
about half the time that Opus 4.5 in
Claude Code took to do the same task.
But I don't know if that's a Gemini
thing or a cursor thing because I have
noticed that when I run Claude models in
cursors agent mode, they actually
execute a lot faster than they do in
cloud code. I think cloud code just
might generally be slower to execute
things for whatever reason, whatever
magic is happening under the hood there.
So, here is the final message and it
gave me the list of URLs and let's let's
go ahead and take a look at that. So,
I'm going to run my server. Okay, so the
first thing I notic is that it doesn't
actually work. So, when I view this this
URL at dashboard, I'm seeing nothing.
So, let's see if we have any issues.
Okay, so here we go. So, here is what
I'm seeing. Let's Let's try out Gemini's
ability to debug this. Seeing a blank
screen and this error. Okay, I'll just
restart the server and see how we're
doing. Huh. So, now we have a syntax
error. Not off to a great start, Gemini.
I'm using CleShot to to grab snapshots
and easily paste them into the chat. I
think that works great. Huh, this is
interesting. Gemini said that it used
layout logs from Lucid React, which does
not exist or was a hallucination. I
don't think I've ever seen an AI agent
admit that it hallucinated. [laughter]
That that is a first for me.
[clears throat] Okay, so now now we're
up and running. Let's see how we're
doing. Okay, so this is this is looking
looking pretty good. I did notice there
was like a a nice little fade in when I
first loaded the page. A little subtle
hover effect. Overall, this feels like a
pretty pretty balanced design. It is
much simpler than the one that Opus 4.5
created. It did give me some quick
actions down here, which is something
that I asked for. And I like the the
navigation up top there. Simple logo.
Good. Let's see if it did dark mode. It
did not.
Again, like it it did this earlier, but
it just didn't do it on on this run. So,
if I go to mobile, let's see how we're
doing there. That's all looking looking
pretty good. Although, this list it
didn't really handle so well on the
smallest size, but I think that's a
common mistake, but something that I
would hope to have worked. Something
that we can clean up for sure. This
Yeah, in that's kind of misaligned. And
we do have a mobile menu, and that's
working well. Okay, so not not so bad
for the dashboard overall. It's It's
kind of clean and consistent. Here's the
client's list. Okay. So, um it's fine,
but yeah, I'm definitely seeing some
issues. So, we've got a weird spacing
issue up here that that probably
shouldn't be there. Um this looks like a
little bit too much top padding. This is
a little bit too close to the edge. So,
again, these are little details that I
could clean up. But to be honest, here
at the end of 2025, I would expect that
a Frontier model like Gemini 3,
especially with all of the uh the
fanfare around it, wouldn't make little
design mistakes like this. But again,
these are easy to clean up. Let's see
how we're doing on mobile. Okay. So, it
it did handle it like this is a
sidescrolling and that's that's a common
way to handle lists, but I did like the
more creative and effective approach
that Cloud Opus took to making sure that
it's list actually stacks in a
responsive way. All right. Now, here is
the invoices list, which is basically
the exact same layout with all of the
same uh design issues. Um, I do like the
consistency. I like how it it didn't
just design a totally separate view from
scratch. it it kept the same consistency
across both, which is what I would want
in an actual application. So, that's
good. Um, okay. So, I did ask it to
create a an invoice editor view, and it
did that. Um, this is simpler, and you
know, I'll I'll just be honest, like
overall my my general sense or my like
the overall look and feel seem to be a
little bit stronger from Opus 4.5, at
least on this run. I mean, I've I've
done a couple different runs, a couple
different projects with these, and
honestly, I've seen both perform really
well and and perform a little bit worse
than one another. They they really sort
of trade off in that sense. Here on this
recording, it seemed like Opus' work
just came out a little bit better than
Gemini so far from what I'm seeing.
Okay, so we've got like we can add new
items. Okay, now I do want to see that
sharable preview, the one that would be
like sent to a client and that would be
this one. Okay, so here is like that
sharable view. Um, and this is
interesting because like normally I
would want this top navigation to not
display since this is something that the
client would see, not the not like the
account user. So, and that's something
that like Opus 4.5 figured out by
default. It had its own layout and
actually if I remember it asked me a
specific question about that during the
upfront planning when I was working with
Opus and then it got it right in the
final implementation and this one Gemini
did not ask me about should there be a
separate layout for the sharable invoice
and here here we are it actually got
that wrong. So that's just a really good
example of a the models being able to
ask smart constructive questions upfront
and b the value of really detail
oriented planning up front leads to a
successful outcome in the end. Okay,
once again we've got like a spacing
issue at the top and we've got some
buttons here. You know, overall it's
it's a clean look and feel. It It looks
fairly professional, but a little bit
more boring than the the nice clean one
created by Opus 4.5. Let's see how we're
doing on mobile. Okay, that works. Super
small. It gets a little bit squashed,
but that's not too big of a deal. This
This gets cut off. And I don't even see
the ability to sides scroll in there.
So, that should stack a little bit
better, but it doesn't. Okay. You know,
overall, I'm being a little bit
nitpicky, and these are all things that
could easily be uh cleaned up, which I
which would normally be what I would do.
Okay, so now that we've established all
the front-end designs for all the key
views and and routes in both
applications, let's circle back and get
the back end all wired up and get this
into almost a shippable state, if you
will. So, I'm going to go back to the
application where we're building with
Claude Opus 4.5 and I'm going to go
ahead and run this prompt 2. And just to
show you what that is, it all it is is
like now that we've designed the front
ends for these pages, let's make a plan
to complete the full backend
implementation for this app. Again, I'm
going to refer to the product overview
for an overview of everything that we're
going for. And I'm telling it like I
want all buttons, navigation links,
functionality should be fully functional
and ready for me to test in a browser.
And then finally, I'm asking it to ask
me clarifying questions to dial in this
plan. Okay. So I'm going to copy that
and I'm going to give that to Claude
code.
Okay. So uh here is the first question.
Okay. So I I'll submit these questions.
So Claude's plan is all set. And here is
that plan summary implementation phases.
Oh, you know what? I I realized I I
think I actually wasn't in plan mode.
And sometimes I forget to toggle between
them. So that's probably what happened
was we actually started the planning of
this, but I wasn't actually technically
in plan mode. So it it did make a plan.
It did ask me clarifying questions
because I asked it to. So you can still
do that even if you're not in plan mode.
But since it wasn't in plan mode, it
sort of just assumed that it was going
to go ahead into implementation, which
is perfectly fine. So, all right, cloud
code and Opus 4.5 is getting to work on
the backend functionality. So, while
that's cooking, I'm going to hop over to
my other project. Now, we're back into
working with Gemini, and we're going to
do the same thing. So, I'm going to stay
in the same chat that I've been working
in, and I'm going to once again use
prompt two. I'm going to copy that into
my prompt here. Again, we're we're sort
of picking up where we've left off.
We've designed the front ends. Now,
we're going to do the backend
implementation. Ask me clarifying
questions. And you know what? This time,
I will go into plan mode. Just making
sure we're we're going to go through the
actual motions here. And I'm asking it
to give me questions. And let's go ahead
with that. All right. So, it's asking
about the pay now button, which I've
already instructed. It should be just a
a mocked up payment form. We're not
going to go through uh the process of
integr integrating payment processing at
this time. Um so we're just going to do
mock only for that. Okay. So I didn't
really see it work, but it did generate
this this plan. But once again, we are
missing the to-dos.
So I'm going to give it one more nudge
to to finish that that to-do list.
Create a to-do list for this plan.
Again, I don't know if that's an issue
with cursors agent mode or maybe Gemini
3 in cursors agent mode, but yeah, that
seemed to happen a few times for me now.
But it did go ahead and add the 10 to-do
items to this plan. I'm going to go
ahead and save the plan just cuz that's
like a a common thing that I do. Okay,
let's go ahead and have it have it
build. I'm just going to switch to agent
mode and proceed with building that
plan. So yeah, actually the UI was a
little funny there with cursor when I
when I have it plan one thing, build
that and then create a second like a
follow-up plan while I'm still using the
same agent. Often times I would just
start up a new agent. It depends on the
project and the the day that I'm
working. But yeah, that that little UI
interaction I thought was a little
confusing in in cursor. Okay, so now
both Gemini 3 is cooking over here and
Claude Code is still working over here.
Okay, so uh they both took roughly about
the same amount of time about 10 12
minutes. And looking at cloud code with
Opus 4.5, here is the the implementation
summary. So that's all ready to go. And
then I see the same thing from Gemini
over here in cursor summary of changes.
Here is everything. Okay, cool. So,
let's go ahead and test out the Opus 4.5
buildout first.
Okay. So, here is the the dashboard for
Invoiceicy. This is built by Opus 4.5.
And you know, the front end still looks
the same as before. Still looking
consistent. And let's try out these
buttons. I'll try new invoice here at
the top. And that that does take me to
the new invoice page. Cool. I can view
all invoices. That's all working fine
from the dashboard. If I click new
client, that links up. Very nice. Uh
let's go back to that client's list and
let's see if we can search for a client.
Yeah, so the search does seem to work.
Nice. Be nice if I could use the
keyboard, but I, you know, that's
something that I can build out. I would
have probably specked for that. Um let's
go ahead and try creating a new client.
Good. That that worked. I had a little
typo there. That's no big deal. Got a
warning modal, a warning alert. That's
good. All right. Let's go ahead and
create an invoice for a client. Okay.
So, I I would have liked it to
automatically select the client, but it
didn't do that even though I had
selected it from the client list. Not a
big deal. It generated an invoice
number.
Calculates, you know, the quantity and
the and the amount correctly. Let's add
another one.
Okay, looking good.
What happens if I click saved draft? And
uh Okay, so I do see an issue here. It
didn't actually save those line items.
So this is so I think that was invoice 9
and I see amount is zero and uh yeah we
don't have those line items saved. So
that is one issue with the
implementation from opus. Let's see if
we can search invoices.
Yeah I can search by client name and I
can search by invoice ID. So that's
nice. Okay so mostly good. There are a
few issues that would need to be worked
out, but that's, you know, it it's
basically all wired up and Opus did a
pretty good job on that, I think.
Now, normally I would go through a bit
of a code review to see how it
structured everything, but that would be
a little bit boring for this YouTube
video. And and also, you know, the the
code style and the tech stack is is just
different for everyone. Um, but I I
wanted to kind of demonstrate the
ability for it to build out a back a
backend and get it functional. So,
that's mostly working. Let's hop over to
the app that is built with Gemini.
Okay, so now I'm running the app that
was built with Gemini 3. Here is the
dashboard for that one. We see total
revenue and I can see that that number
is correct because it's adding up uh
just the paid invoices and not the
pending and the draft. So that's that's
good. And then yeah, outstanding
includes these two. Uh we've got some
active clients. That's all looking good.
If we create a new invoice, we can get
to that from here. We can add a new
client from here. Good. Let's go to the
clients list. Let's see if the search
works. It doesn't seem to work. Okay.
So, it did not actually wire up that
search. I didn't specifically tell it to
do that, but I did specifically say I
wanted all functionality and, you know,
features to be functional and ready for
me to test in the browser. So, you know,
that's something that it didn't quite
follow my instruction on.
Um, yeah. So, these these are actually
not functional either. So, these
actions, nothing happens. Let's try
creating a new client.
Okay, we've got an issue when we uh try
to create a new client. We've got an
error there. Let's just go ahead and and
and try to create a new invoice. I can
select a client. I'll create a line
item.
We've got a little overlapping UI issue
there. That's not great. I would want to
clean that up.
Okay, so we have the total and that
appears to be correct. Let's save that.
And yeah, once again, we have an issue
with with saving. So, I'm going to try
to have it debug that. Let's Let's try
to do it. So, what I did was I cleared
my server logs. I'm going to try to
create I get the error and not much is
showing there.
error when trying to create an invoice.
Same happens when creating
a client. So hopefully I can fix both of
those in one shot. Now I want to be
clear this entire design and build
process was very uh abbreviated and and
fast build out uh really just for demo
purposes. Normally I would spend a lot
more time upfront in the planning and
the spec and architectural uh phase and
that would prevent a lot of these issues
when we when we come down the line to a
final implementation and that's really
the whole essence of spec driven
development. But for the purpose of this
video I wanted to just sort of like
quickly design and build an app with
both Opus and Gemini 3. Okay. So it says
that it has fixed the error. Let's see
about that
and I will refresh and let's Okay, so
that does seem to have saved. Okay, so
that basically works. So in the end on
my first run, I must say these newest
models don't seem noticeably different,
but I expect that their true power will
be revealed as I use them dayto-day
going forward. I think my real takeaway
from this is that these Frontier models
are converging. They're all incredibly
capable now and they're only going to
keep getting better, which means the gap
between the models matters less and less
over time. What matters more is you and
me. It's our ability to leverage these
tools, our product instincts, our
architectural decisions, our taste.
That's the real unfair advantage in this
new era. Not which model we're using,
but how skilled we are at directing
them. And that's exactly why I made a
video breaking down the five essential
skills that matter most for builders.
Now, for some of them, you might already
have an unfair advantage. A few of them
are totally new domains that didn't even
exist a year or two ago. So, right after
you hit subscribe on this channel, I'll
see you over there next. Let's keep
building.